Finding aid to Record Group 9. Photographs, of the YWCA of the U.S.A. records SSC.MS.00324.RG9
Sophia Smith Collection
- Prints and negatives, 1
  - International Work, D
    - Papua New Guinea, 1967; 1972 (Box 1016, Folder 11)
      Photographs young women's Christian association programs and buildings in Papua New Guinea including an occupational training program for girls who left school and a dedication service for a new building.
      Papua New Guinea; Young Women's Christian associations -- Papua New Guinea
    - Peru, circa 1910-1969; bulk 1962-1969 (Box 1016, Folder 12)
      Photographs of young women's Christian association programs, services, leaders, and members. Programs and services include cooking classes, teenage member volunteer programs and English language clubs for young employed women. Additional photographs include the first meeting of the YWCA of Lima and images of rural and urban life in Peru.
      Peru; Young Women's Christian associations -- Peru; Women -- Peru; Rural women -- Peru; Women -- Employment -- Peru; Teenage girls -- Peru; Children -- Peru
    - Philippines: Buildings, circa 1927-1971 (Box 1016, Folder 13)
      Interior and exterior photographs of young women's Christian association buildings in rural and urban communities in the Philippines. Some photographs show buildings and facilities in use.
      Philippines; Young Women's Christian associations -- Philippines; Women -- Philippines; Women -- International cooperation
    - Philippines: Camps, conferences, and groups, circa 1924-1972 (Box 1016, Folder 14)
      Photographs of conferences, meetings, camps and programs of the young women's Christian associations in the Philippines.
      Philippines; Young Women's Christian associations -- Philippines; Women -- Philippines; Camps -- Philippines; Recreation -- Philippines; Women -- International cooperation; Leadership in women; Outdoor recreation -- Philippines; Women -- Employment -- Philippines; Congresses and conventions -- Philippines
    - Philippines: Health and nutrition, 1948-1968 (Box 1016, Folder 15)
      Photographs of young women's Christian association health programs in the Philippines including clinics, health education, supplemental nutrition and a swimming class for youth with cerebral palsy.
      Philippines; Young Women's Christian associations -- Philippines; Women -- Philippines; Rural health services -- Philippines; Health education -- Philippines; Swimming -- Philippines
    - Philippines: Negatives (Box 1017, Folder 1-3)
    - Phillippines: Physical education, circa 1935-1963 (Box 1017, Folder 4)
      Photographs of physical education classes for women and children at young women's Christian associations in the Philippines. Classes represented include swimming, Judo, ballet, and general fitness.
      Philippines; Young Women's Christian associations -- Philippines; Swimming -- Philippines; Physical education for women -- Philippines; Women -- Philippines; Recreation -- Philippines; Children -- Philippines; Judo -- Philippines
    - Philippines: Program, 1933-1989 (Box 1017, Folder 5)
      Photographs depicting the programs, classes, and services of young women's Christian associations in the Philippines. Program elements represented include international programs, a craft goods shop, sewing and dressmaking, hunger relief and nutrition education, Week of Prayer for Christian Unity services, job counseling, and basic education programs.
      Philippines; Young Women's Christian associations -- Philippines; Health education -- Philippines; Women -- Philippines; Children -- Philippines; Handicraft -- Philippines; Women -- International cooperation; Literacy -- Philippines; Basic Education -- Philippines; Women -- Religious life -- Philippines; Vocational guidance -- Philippines
    - Philippines: Recreation and dance, circa 1942-1973 (Box 1017, Folder 6)
      Photographs of recreation programs at young women's Christian associations in the Philippines. Recreation classes and programs include swimming, hikes, folk and social dancing, outdoor recreation and more and include classes for children through adult.
      Philippines; Women -- Philippines; Young Women's Christian associations -- Philippines; Recreation -- Philippines; Outdoor recreation -- Philippines; Swimming -- Philippines; Dance -- Philippines; Children -- Philippines
    - Philippines: Teens, circa 1936-1968 (Box 1017, Folder 7)
      Photographs of the teenage programs of young women's Christian associations in the Philippines. Photographs show teen leadership, conferences and special events, service projects, classes and groups.
      Philippines; Handicraft -- Philippines; Young Women's Christian associations -- Philippines; Dance -- Philippines; Teenage girls -- Philippines; Leadership in adolescents -- Philippines
    - Philippines: Women at work, circa 1918-1974 (Box 1017, Folder 8)
      Photographs depicting women engaged in employment in the Philippines as well as photographs of young women's Christian association programs supporting women's employment. YWCA programs include livestock programs helping women in rural areas and providing sewing machines and instruction. Additional photographs feature nurses training, a group crafting plastic butterflies for the YWCA of the USA national convention, and a work program for women prisoners.
      Philippines; Women -- Employment -- Philippines; Vocational guidance -- Philippines; Women -- Philippines; Young Women's Christian associations -- Philippines; Women prisoners -- Philippines
    - Poland, circa 1918-1923 (Box 1017, Folder 9)
      Photographs of young women's Christian association programs and activities in Poland including images of war work activity, an American YWCA in Warsaw, Poland, and camp programs.
      Poland; Young Women's Christian associations -- Poland; Women -- Poland; World War, 1914-1918 -- War work
    - Album, YWCA of Warsaw, Poland, n.d. (Box 1052)
    - Romania, circa 1920-1922 (Box 1017, Folder 10)
      Group photographs and one portrait of young women's Christian association members in Romania.
      Romania; Women -- Romania; Young Women's Christian associations -- Romania
    - Russia: General, circa 1910-1919 (Box 1017, Folder 11)
      Photographs of Russian communities, groups, and young women's Christian associations.
      Russia; Young Women's Christian associations -- Russia; Women -- Russia; Russia -- Rural conditions
    - Russia: Photo reports from Archangel and Vladivostok, circa 1919 (Box 1017, Folder 12)
      Two photographic reports from Russia featuring young women's Christian associations and local life.
      Arkhangelsk, Arkhangel'skaya Oblast', Russia; Vladivostok, Primorskiy Kray, Russia; Young Women's Christian associations -- Russia; Women -- Russia; Russia -- Rural conditions; scrapbooks; reports
    - Sierra Leone, 1954-1970 (Box 1017, Folder 13, Box 1018, Folder 1)
      Photographs of young women's Christian association buildings, programs, leaders and members in Sierra Leone.
      Sierra Leone; Women -- Sierra Leone; Young Women's Christian associations -- Sierra Leone; Vocational guidance -- Sierra Leone; Day camps -- Sierra Leone
    - Singapore, 1970 (Box 1018, Folder 2)
      Children playing with water and a hose at a child care center in Singapore.
      Singapore; Children -- Singapore
    - Somalia, 1982 (Box 1018, Folder 3)
      Photograph of a woman making a basket in Somalia.
      Somalia; Women -- Somalia
    - South Africa: Buildings, circa 1960-1970 (Box 1018, Folder 4)
      Photographs of young women's Christian association building, dedication celebrations, and group breaking ceremonies in South Africa.
      South Africa; Women -- South Africa; Young Women's Christian associations -- South Africa
    - South Africa: Children, 1966-1969 (Box 1018, Folder 5)
      Photographs of young women's Christian association programs and services for children and youth in South Africa including, recreation programs, child care services, and educational opportunities.
      South Africa; Young Women's Christian associations -- South Africa; Women -- South Africa; Children -- South Africa; Youth -- South Africa; Child care services -- South Africa; Recreation -- South Africa
    - South Africa: Classes, circa 1967 (Box 1018, Folder 6)
      Photographs of handicraft, sewing, and health education classes at young women's Christian associations in South Africa.
      Women -- South Africa; South Africa; Young Women's Christian associations -- South Africa; Handicraft -- South Africa; Health education -- South Africa
    - South Africa: Conferences and groups, circa 1957-1987 (Box 1018, Folder 7)
      Photographs from conferences and conventions of young women's Christian associations in South Africa.
      South Africa; Women -- South Africa; Young Women's Christian associations -- South Africa; Youth -- South Africa; Congresses and conventions -- South Africa; Leadership in women
    - South Africa: Consultation in New York, 1987 (Box 1018, Folder 8)
      Photographs from a consultation on South Africa at the offices of the YWCA of the U.S.A. National Board in New York City.
      South Africa; Women -- South Africa; Young Women's Christian associations -- South Africa; Women -- International cooperation; Leadership in women; Young Women's Christian Association of the U.S.A. National Board
    - South Africa: Program, circa 1959-1969 (Box 1018, Folder 9)
      Photographs of the programs, services, and activities of young women's Christian associations in South Africa including Christmas pageants, a program for disabled youth, maternity care, and leadership training.
      South Africa; Recreation -- South Africa; Children -- South Africa; Women -- South Africa; Young Women's Christian associations -- South Africa; Women -- International cooperation; Christmas pageants -- South Africa; Children with disabilities -- South Africa
    - South America, circa 1920-1967 (Box 1018, Folder 10)
      Photographs from unidentified South American countries or pertaining to the overall program of young women's Christian associations in South America. In addition to photographs, there are single pages removed from the book "With the Blue Triangle South: A history of the Buenos Aires Young Women's Christian Association 1890-1940."
      Women -- South America; Young Women's Christian associations -- South America; Recreation -- South America; Women -- International cooperation
    - Sri Lanka, circa 1910-1976 (Box 1018, Folder 11)
      Photographs of programs, camps, classes and buildings of young women's Christian associations in Sri Lanka.
      Sri Lanka; Women -- Sri Lanka; Young Women's Christian associations -- Sri Lanka; Women -- Employment -- Sri Lanka; Recreation -- Sri Lanka; Contact sheets; Children -- Sri Lanka; Leadership in women
    - St. Vincent, 1972 (Box 1018, Folder 12)
      Photograph of a young women's Christian association building on the island of Saint Vincent.
      Saint Vincent, Saint Vincent and the Grenadines; Young Women's Christian associations -- Saint Vincent
    - Suriname, circa 1968-1972 (Box 1018, Folder 13)
      Photographs of programs, buildings and members of young women's Christian associations in Suriname.
      Suriname; Young Women's Christian associations -- Suriname; Women -- Suriname
    - Sweden, 1964 (Box 1018, Folder 14)
      Two photographs from the YWCA of Chicago depicting women demonstrating traditional Swedish dress and crafts.
      YWCA of Chicago, Illinois
    - Syria, circa 1910-1962 (Box 1018, Folder 15)
      Photographs of young women's Christian association programs and members in Syria as well as several photographs of local scenes. A description on the back of a photograph of a kindergarten class indicates uncertainty as to its location. Syria in crossed out and Korea And Thailand are followed by question marks.
      Syria; Women -- Syria; Young Women's Christian associations -- Syria
    - Taiwan: Buildings, circa 1955-1973 (Box 1018, Folder 16)
      Photographs of the exteriors and interiors of young women's Christian associations in Taiwan.
      Taiwan; Young Women's Christian associations -- Taiwan; Women -- Taiwan
    - Taiwan: Camping, circa 1950-1969 (Box 1018, Folder 17)
      Photographs of camp programs from young women's Christian associations in Taiwan. Camp programs photographed include swimming and other seaside recreation, crafts, religious services, meals, and hiking.
      Taiwan; Young Women's Christian associations -- Taiwan; Women -- Taiwan; Youth -- Taiwan; Camps -- Taiwan; Outdoor recreation -- Taiwan; Handicraft -- Taiwan; Swimming -- Taiwan
    - Taiwan: Children, circa 1966-1968 (Box 1018, Folder 18)
      Photographs of programs and activities for children at young women's Christian associations in Taiwan. Programs include nurseries and child care services, kindergartens, day camps, and milk stations.
      Taiwan; Young Women's Christian associations -- Taiwan; Women -- Taiwan; Children -- Taiwan; Child care services -- Taiwan; Food relief -- Taiwan; Day camps -- Taiwan; Christmas pageants -- Taiwan
    - Taiwan: Classes, 1958-1968 (Box 1019, Folder 1)
      Photographs of young women's Christian association classes in Taiwan. Classes offered by YWCA's in Taiwan supplement basic education, provide skills training or provide instruction in arts. Classes photographed include first aid, Japanese flower arranging, cooking and baking, literacy and a mother's club.
      Taiwan; Young Women's Christian associations -- Taiwan; Women -- Taiwan; Vocational guidance -- Taiwan; Literacy -- Taiwan; Cooking -- Study and teaching -- Taiwan; Handicraft -- Taiwan
    - Taiwan: Miscellaneous, circa 1940-1972 (Box 1019, Folder 2)
      Photographs of young women's Christian association special programs, classes, members and activities in Tawain including World Membership Day programs, a white elephant sale, programs for early school leavers and assorted classes. In addition, there are unlabeled photographs of groups and outdoor activities.
      Taiwan; Youth -- Taiwan; Young Women's Christian associations -- Taiwan; Leadership in women; Women -- International cooperation; Children -- Taiwan; Women -- Taiwan; Cooking -- Study and teaching -- Taiwan; Outdoor recreation -- Taiwan
    - Tanzania, circa 1960-1969 (Box 1019, Folder 3)
      Photographs of young women's Christian association buildings, members, leaders and programs in Tanzania. Photographed programs include nursery schools, adult education, a cottage industry program, and job skills training.
      Tanzania; Women -- Tanzania; Young Women's Christian associations -- Tanzania; Children -- Tanzania; Child care services -- Tanzania; Leadership in women; Vocational guidance -- Tanzania
    - Thailand: Bazaars and fashion shows, 1953-1958 (Box 1019, Folder 4)
      Photographs of bazaars, fashion shows and home decorating shows from young women's Christian associations in Thailand. These special events, often held as fundraisers, demonstrate local and international tradition, dress and craft as a way of highlighting local and international custom and fostering world fellowship.
      Thailand; Young Women's Christian associations -- Thailand; Women -- Thailand; Women -- International cooperation; Traditional dress -- Thailand; Fund raising
    - Thailand: Buildings, 1947-1968 (Box 1019, Folder 5)
      Photographs of young women's Christian association buildings in Thailand.
      Thailand; Young Women's Christian associations -- Thailand
    - Thailand: Children and teens, 1954-1971 (Box 1019, Folder 6)
      Photographs of children and teenagers participating in young women's Christian association programs in Thailand. Youth programs include nurseries for young children, Y-Teen programs, and a student hostel.
      Thailand; Young Women's Christian associations -- Thailand; Children -- Thailand; Teenage girls -- Thailand; Square dancing; Recreation -- Thailand; Child care services -- Thailand; Women -- International cooperation
    - Thailand: Classes, circa 1950-1968 (Box 1019, Folder 7)
      Photographs of young women's Christian association classes for youth and adults in Thailand including English language, nutrition, cooking, sewing, flower arranging, swimming, and small industries.
      Women -- Thailand; Thailand; Young Women's Christian associations -- Thailand; Children -- Thailand; Recreation -- Thailand; Flower arrangement, Japanese; Nutrition -- Study and teaching -- Thailand; Cooking -- Study and teaching -- Thailand; English language -- Study and teaching -- Thailand; Swimming -- Thailand; Sewing -- Thailand
    - Thailand: Miscellaneous, 1954-1974 (Box 1019, Folder 8)
      Photographs of young women's Christian association programs and leaders in Thailand. Photographs include images of Marian Anderson visiting a Y-Teen group, a television production of "Snow White," Queen Sirikit visiting a YWCA bazaar, and additional images of members and leaders.
      Thailand; Young Women's Christian associations -- Thailand; Teenage girls -- Thailand; Women -- Thailand; Women -- Employment -- Thailand; Leadership in women; Women -- International cooperation; Anderson, Marian, 1897-1993; Sirikit, Queen, consort of Bhumibol Adulyadej, King of Thailand, 1932-
    - Thailand: Negatives, circa 1950-1970 (Box 1019, Folder 9-10)
      Negatives from the photograph series of young women's Christian associations in Thailand. Some negatives are accompanied by their corresponding positive and these photographs were digitized. Negatives were not digitized.
      Thailand; Young Women's Christian associations -- Thailand; Women -- Thailand
    - Trinidad and Tobago, 1967 (Box 1019, Folder 11)
      Group photographs of members of young women's Christian associations in Trinidad and Tobago.
      Trinidad and Tobago
    - Turkey: Buildings, circa 1954-1989 (Box 1019, Folder 12)
      Photographs of buildings and communities in Turkey including images of young women's Christian associations.
      Turkey; Young Women's Christian associations -- Turkey
    - Turkey: Camping and recreation, circa 1920-1970 (Box 1019, Folder 13, Box 1020, Folder 1-3)
      Photographs of young women's Christian association camp and recreation programs in Turkey including a 1932 scrapbook of the summer camp of the Istanbul service centers, Cadde Bostan.
      Turkey; Young Women's Christian associations -- Turkey; Recreation -- Turkey; Outdoor recreation -- Turkey; Camps -- Turkey; Amateur plays; Swimming -- Turkey
    - Turkey: Children, circa 1950-1973 (Box 1020, Folder 4)
      Photographs of programs for children and teens at young women's Christian associations in Turkey. Programs photographed include services for orphans, day care, kindergartens, a children's library, recreation programs, day camps, nursery care for children of women prisoners and Girl Reserves.
      Turkey; Young Women's Christian associations -- Turkey; Recreation -- Turkey; Refugees -- Turkey; Camps -- Turkey; Children -- Turkey; Child care services -- Turkey; Handicraft -- Turkey
    - Turkey: Classes, circa 1926-1969 (Box 1020, Folder 5-6)
      Photographs of vocational training classes at young women's Christian associations in Turkey. Photographed classes include typing, languages, sewing, and shorthand.
      Turkey; Young Women's Christian associations -- Turkey; Women -- Turkey; Occupational training -- Turkey
    - Turkey: Constantinople, circa 1920-1964 (Box 1020, Folder 7-9)
      Photographs of young women's Christian association programs, buildings, services and activities in Turkey as well as photographs of local people, scenes, and buildings. Early YWCA photographs feature programs at the Garden of Happiness camp, Pera Gymnasium, and Stambul Garden centers and later photographs include other programs and centers in Istanbul and vocational training.
      Turkey; İstanbul, Turkey; Women -- Turkey; Young Women's Christian associations -- Turkey; Children -- Turkey; Swimming -- Turkey; Outdoor recreation -- Turkey; Occupational training -- Turkey; Recreation -- Turkey; Turkey -- Religious life and customs
    - Turkey: Miscellaneous, circa 1945-1983 (Box 1020, Folder 10)
      Photographs of special events and services of young women's Christian Associations in Turkey. Photographs include an image of American prisoners of war in the YWCA of Istanbul, a photograph of a YWCA member looking a silver tray, a photograph of a woman at an art show and a series of photographs taken at the sixtieth anniversary of the Amerikan Lisan Ve Sanat Dersanesi.
      Turkey; Young Women's Christian associations -- Turkey; Women -- Turkey; Occupational training -- Turkey; Leadership in women
    - Turkey: Smyrna and Cilicia, circa 1921-1923 (Box 1020, Folder 11-12)
      Photographs of young women's Christian association programs and activities in the areas of Smyrna and Cilicia in addition to photographs of the local people and living conditions followed by a series of photographs documenting the plight of the refugee after the Great Fire of Smyrna. YWCA photographs mostly feature young women enjoying summer camp activities. Additional photographs of Smyrna and Cilicia include images of refugee families and living conditions and well as scenes of landscapes and towns. Photographs of the Great Fire of Smyrna include images of refugees awaiting transport, refugees waiting and arriving in Greece and images of transport boats.
      Turkey; Izmir, İzmir, Turkey; Refugees -- Turkey; Women -- Turkey; Young Women's Christian associations -- Turkey; Cilicia, Turkey; Refugees -- Greece; Greco-Turkish War, 1921-1922 -- Atrocities; Camps -- Turkey; Refugees -- Armenia
    - Uganda: Agricultural training, circa 1959-1967 (Box 1020, Folder 13, Box 1021, Folder 1)
      Photographs of young women's Christian association agriculture training programs in Uganda.
      Uganda; Young Women's Christian associations -- Uganda; Women -- Uganda; Agriculture -- Uganda; Agriculture -- Study and teaching
    - Uganda: Buildings and conferences, 1955-1963 (Box 1021, Folder 2)
      Photographs of young women's Christian association buildings in Uganda as well as group photographs of delegates to conferences. Building photographs include photographs of the opening ceremonies for the YWCA of Uganda hostel.
      Uganda; Young Women's Christian associations -- Uganda; Women -- Uganda; Congresses and conventions -- Uganda; Special events -- Uganda; Leadership in women; Women -- International cooperation
    - Uganda: Classes and crafts, circa 1953-1970 (Box 1021, Folder 3-4)
      Photographs of young women's Christian association classes in Uganda. Classes include crafts, nutrition, cooking, sewing and vocational training. The reverse of two photographs have the handwritten caption "YWCA of Nigeria National Crafts Shop." It is not known at the time of description if this placement was in error or intentional.
      Uganda; Young Women's Christian associations -- Uganda; Women -- Uganda; Handicraft -- Uganda; Adult education of women -- Uganda; Women -- Employment -- Uganda
    - Uganda: Groups and meetings, circa 1953-1969 (Box 1021, Folder 5-6)
      Photographs of young women's Christian association groups, meetings, programs and events in Uganda.
      Uganda; Young Women's Christian associations -- Uganda; Women -- Uganda; Special events -- Uganda; Leadership in women; Women -- International cooperation
    - Uganda: Health and nutrition, circa 1953-1961 (Box 1021, Folder 7)
      Photographs of health and nutrition programs in young women's Christian associations in Uganda. Photographed programs include cooking classes, childcare and parenting classes, a visit to an infant malnutrition lab as part of an agriculture course, and nutrition education. Photographs also include an image of a group of nurses that are part of the YWCA of Uganda.